this video is going to define
这部影片将要定义
coalitional games and explain what
联盟游戏并解释什么
they're used for
他们用于
so coalitional games unlike the non
所以联盟游戏不像非
cooperative games that we've talked
我们谈论过的合作游戏
about so far don't model individual
到目前为止，不要为个人建模
agents taking actions instead they think
代理商采取行动，反而他们认为
about groups of agents acting together
关于一群特工一起行动
so the idea is going to be that we think
所以我们的想法是
about a set of agents and ask about what
关于一组代理，并询问什么
coalitions could form what groups of
联盟可以形成什么团体
agents could choose to work together and
特工可以选择一起工作
to do that we're going to define how
为此，我们将定义如何
well each different group of agents is
每个不同的代理商群体
able to do for itself now in particular
现在能够自己做
in a coalitional game we're not going to
在联盟游戏中，我们不会
think about how the agents individually
考虑一下代理商如何单独
divide work up within the coalition or
在联盟内部划分工作或
how it is that they coordinate with each
他们如何与每个人协调
other in order to form a coalition we're
为了组成一个联盟，我们
going to take all of that as given and
将所有这些都视为给定的
instead just think about how the
而是考虑一下
coalition does all together what kinds
联盟一起做什么
of payoffs they're able to achieve we're
他们能够实现的回报
going to begin by making an assumption
首先要做一个假设
that it's called transferable utility
被称为可转移的实用程序
what this assumption means is that it's
这个假设的意思是
possible for a coalition to redistribute
联盟有可能重新分配
the value that it's able to achieve
它能够实现的价值
arbitrarily among its members so for
在其成员中任意
example if the coalition is paid its
例如，如果联盟获得报酬
value and money it would be possible to
价值和金钱，将有可能
divide up that money and make side
分配那笔钱并赚钱
payments among the members in any way in
会员之间以任何方式付款
general what this assumption amounts to
通常，这个假设等于
is that we'll be able to assign some
是我们可以分配一些
single value as the payoff to a
单一价值作为收益
coalition and trust that it can be
联盟和信任它可以
arbitrarily divided up among the members
在成员之间任意分配
under this assumption here's how we can
在这种假设下，我们可以
define a coalitional game a coalitional
定义一个联盟游戏，一个联盟
game has two parts n and V where as in
游戏分为n和V两部分，其中
the previous models we've thought about
我们之前考虑过的模型
before n is just a finite set of players
在n只是有限的一组玩家之前
and we'll again index this by eye when
我们将再次通过肉眼索引
we want to talk about individual players
我们想谈谈个人玩家
in the set and the kind of acts like our
在场景和像我们这样的行为中
utility function for a coalitional game
联合游戏的效用函数
it says for every subset of the players
它说，对于每个玩家子集
s so for every coalition s that could
对于每个可能的联盟
form up to and including all of the
构成并包括所有
players in the game what is the payoff V
玩家在游戏中的收益是多少
of s that the coalition can achieve and
联盟可以实现的
this of course will allow the coalition
这当然会允许联盟
to divide up among its members will make
在其成员之间进行划分将使
a normalizing assumption that the value
归一化的假设
of the empty set is zero there are two
空集为零有两个
typical questions that we want to ask
我们想问的典型问题
using coalitional game theory the two
用联盟博弈论两个
kind of fundamental questions the first
第一种基本问题
is which coalition makes sense to form
哪个联盟才有意义
which coalition would would like to form
哪个联盟想成立
in this game and secondly once we know
在这个游戏中，第二，一旦我们知道
which coalition will form how should the
哪个联盟将形成
coalition divide its payoff amongst all
联盟将收益分配给所有人
of the people in the coalition now we're
联盟中的人现在
not going to spend very much effort
不会花很多力气
thinking about the first question it's
考虑第一个问题
usually going to be the case that the
通常情况下，
answer is the so-called grand coalition
答案就是所谓的大联盟
which means everybody so usually all of
这意味着每个人通常都
the agents will agree to work together
代理商将同意一起工作
however sometimes in order to guarantee
但是有时为了保证
that this would be true we have to be
这是真的，我们必须
careful about thinking about how the
仔细考虑如何
coalition will divide its payoffs among
联盟将把收益分配给
its members in particular here's a kind
它的成员特别是一种
of game that that helps us to think
有助于我们思考的游戏
about the first question we say that a
关于第一个问题，我们说一个
coalitional game is super additive if
联盟博弈是超级加法，如果
for all pairs of coalition's s and T
对于联盟的所有T和T
which are both strict subsets of n if
如果n都是n的严格子集
the intersection between these two
这两者之间的交集
coalition's is empty which means these
联盟是空的，这意味着
two coalition's involve entirely
两个联盟完全参与
different sets of agents then if we make
如果我们做不同的代理商
a new coalition S Union T that combines
结合了新的联盟S Union T
these two coalition's together the value
这两个联盟的价值
of this larger coalition is at least as
这个更大的联盟至少
big as the sum of the values of the two
与两者之和大
coalition's independent
联盟的独立
so in other words if I make a bigger
换句话说，如果我做一个更大的
coalition out of two independent
两个独立联盟
coalition's the value of that bigger
联盟的价值更大
coalition is always at least as big as
联盟总是至少与
the some of the values that those two
那两个的一些价值
independent coalition's were able to get
独立联盟的能够
on their own
他们自己
this assumption makes sense if it's
如果这个假设是合理的
possible for coalition's to always work
联盟永远可以工作的可能
without interfering with each other and
而不互相干扰
this is often an assumption that we make
这通常是我们做的一个假设
in a coalitional game
在联合游戏中
notice that this super additive 'ti
注意，这种超级添加剂
assumption implies that the highest
假设意味着最高
payoff of all at least the weekly
至少每周一次的回报
highest payoff of all is achieved by the
最高的回报是通过
grand coalition so when we're thinking
大联盟，所以当我们在思考
about a super additive game it's natural
关于超级加法游戏，这很自然
to think that the grand coalition would
认为大联盟会
want to form so in answer to the first
想要形成以回应第一个
of the questions that I talked about
我谈论的问题中
before we're going to tend to assume
在我们倾向于假设之前
that the grand coalition forms and we're
大联盟形成，我们
going to focus on this second question
将专注于第二个问题
of how the coalition ought to divide its
联盟应该如何划分其
payoff now
现在还清
it's reasonable to wonder what I mean
想知道我的意思是合理的
when I say how it ought to divide its
当我说应该如何划分
payoff that kind of depends on what the
这种收益取决于
Coalition is trying to achieve and we're
联盟正在努力实现目标，我们正在
going to consider two different ways of
将考虑两种不同的方式
answering that question the first is how
首先回答这个问题
it ought to divide its payoff if what
它应该分摊收益，如果
it's concerned with is fairness secondly
其次是公平
we might instead wonder about how it
我们可能反而想知道它如何
ought to divide its payoff if what it's
应该将收益分成两部分
concerned about is stability by which we
关注的是我们的稳定性
mean everybody would be willing to form
意味着每个人都愿意形成
the coalition rather than instead
联盟而不是
forming smaller coalition's because they
形成较小的联盟，因为他们
might be able to achieve higher value
也许能够实现更高的价值
for themselves and we'll look at all of
为自己，我们将研究所有
this in the videos that follow
在接下来的视频中